# **TUSHAR DAS**

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

+91-7209748142

tushardas@wandererdroid.in

in @tshrds

profile.wandererdroid.in

Pengaluru

### **PROFILE**

As a back-end engineer, Tushar specializes in building end-to-end applications and has around 8 years of relevant experience in IT.

He has worked with product teams catering to versatile customers ranging from Pharmaceuticals, Consumer Staple, HRMS, Tech-Ed and BFSI.

Tushar is a design-minded developer with good communication, interpersonal and problem-solving abilities, and likes to add value to the team to help boost Companies' data management efficiency.

## **EDUCATION**

B.Tech in Computer Science and Technology from West Bengal University of Technology (2011 -2015)

### **EXPERTISE**

### Languages:

- Java/J2EE
- AngularJS1
- Python

### Databases:

- RDBMS
- MongoDB
- Neo4J
- Snowflake
- Parquet/Delta Table

### Frameworks:

• Spring MVC & Hibernate

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### SENIOR PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

# Calibo India Pvt Ltd

Apr 2021 - Present

#### **LAZSA Platform**

This project is a Integrated Business Digital Platform is a state-ofthe-art platform that accelerates the various stages of your digital innovation journey to help you deliver digital solutions quickly and in a unified manner.

- Domain: PPaaS
- Creating REST end-points to serve business requirement.
- Worked on NiFi Integration on various templates such as:
   Kafka to Snowflake, Kafka to Hadoop, FTP to MySQL, etc
- Introduced Metabase as a tech-stack (using docker container), which helps in visualization.
- Introduced Open-Refine as a tech-stack (using docker container), and added common transformations for easy data transform.
- Implemented S3 integration using AWS SDK.
- Implemented app creation and visualization in Qlik-Sense Technology.
- Was involved in creating DevOps pipeline using Jenkins CI/CD and deploying micro-services in AWS Kubernetes Cluster.
- Worked on python notebook to create a template to be used as AWS Kinesis Stream to S3 bucket pipeline.
- Introduced multi-object pipelines for AWS AppFlow.
- Worked on python wheel packages to be used in Databricks Notebook for integration.
- Worked on security fixes using sync and removed critical and high vulnerabilities from application

### **SENIOR ENGINEER**

# Altimetrik India Pvt Ltd

July 2015 - Mar 2021

# 1. Integrated Business Development Platform (BDP)

This project is a platform which integrates multiple technologies at a single platform for the developers. This follows the approach of all the pioneers building blocks: No Code, Low Code, and Pro Code. This will help customers to enhance their productivity. BDP is a platform, which provides multiple modules such as, techstack development, agile integrations, data integrations, with multiple dashboards and charts to visualize performance. It's a single platform where the user can Define, Design, Develop & Deploy.

- · Domain: PaaS
- Worked on Agile Integration using JIRA and Trello APIs.
- Worked on NiFi Integration: service endpoints to facilitate dataflow, design dataflow templates.
- Integrating AWS sdk for S3 integrations as a datasource for multiple technologies.
- Integrated Metabase and Qlik Sense as a data visualizations tools.

- Spring Boot & JPA
- Angular 1
- · Python Whl

### Methodologies:

- Agile
- Waterfall

### **Development Tools:**

- IntelliJ
- Eclipse
- PyCharm
- Visual Studio Code
- Postman

## Dependency Manager:

- Gradle
- Maven

### Visualization Tools:

- Qlik Sense
- Metabase

### Soft Skills:

- Leadership
- Creativity
- Project Management
- · Problem Solving

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Recipient of multiple Inspire and Integrity Awards for consistent performance excellence
- Recipient of Gem Award at Calibo
- Visited Uruguay for business meet and to facilitate peerprogramming with their team.
- Recipient of Spot
   Award at Altimetrik for
   exceptional
   performance in
   PLAYGROUND
- Winner of College
   Hackathon for building
   an enterprise
   application to meet the
   Organ Donation
   problem.

### 2. Playground

This project shapes and grooms talent, brings technology and engineering excellence, and provides us an opportunity to help our customers on their transformational initiatives. It also has a new approach to hiring high quality talent. It also included online test integration with third party services, creating amazon workspaces, undergoing various skill- based trainings to uplift the employees.

- Domain: HRMS
- Creating REST end-points to serve business requirement.
- Creating orchestrating layer end-point in nodeJS to interact UI with the back-end services.
- Integrating AWS sdk APIs to create workspaces and allow user to use the space in the aws directory.
- Integrating SDFC Sandbox APIs to create workspace for users.
- Eclipse CHE integration to enable users to use a cloud based workspace for development.

#### 3. Platform-API E&M

This project is about creating various API's using Spring Boot and exposing each one of them as a different service. All the services are managed through a gateway channel, and the REST services are invoked via Swagger-UI template.

- · Domain: RestFull Services
- Integrating with phabricator git service for all git functionalities.
- Writing end services for spring cloud dataflow microservices.
- Building components with Spring-boot micro-services, Neo4j Graph DB
- Writing Junit Test cases.

### 4. Platform-WeaVon

This project is about creating a code generator in almost every possible language to atleast setup the base structure before creating an application. This will also support multiple databases as mysql, postgress, mongo, neo4j, etc. It will also include CI & CD process to directly integrate with github and deploy in a server for its use.

- Domain: Data Platform
- Writing application end services to integrate docker.
- Writing front-end view using template based architecture.
- Working on dynamic injection of templates using react and handlebar.
- Supported software integration and implemented maintenance enhancements to bolster product development cycle

### 5. AltiFin - Paysa

This project is about building a robust remittance application which will allow the fund transfer for the rural immigrant population at a low service charge.

- · Domain: BFSI
- Writing application end services to integrate with the Bank (initially RBL Bank, later switched to Axis Bank) APIs.
- Writing application end services to create file-uploader and other CRUD related services.
- Creating front end Angular design application to call and receive REST responses.